

SENIOR WEB & UI/UX DEVELOPER

A seasoned Senior Web and User Interface (UI/UX) Developer with 12+ years of experience, known for collaborating with diverse clients and organizations. Excels in crafting clean, maintainable code and delivering engaging web designs, harmonizing creative UI design with rigorous and meticulous development.

SKILLS

Core Skills

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • TypeScript • UX Development & Design

Additional Skills

 Adobe Creative Cloud
Amazon Web Services (AWS)
Angular
Auth0
Babel
Bitbucket
Bootstrap
CakePHP CodeIgniter • Contentful • CSS Animations & Keyframes • CSS Preprocessors (SASS/SCSS/LESS) • CSS Variables & Custom Properties • Docker • Drupal • Figma • Firebase • Git • GitHub • Grunt • Gulp • Handlebars • InVision • JAMstack • JIRA • jQuery • LAMP/MAMP • Laravel • Liquid (Shopify) • Material Design • MEAN/MERN • MySQL • Next.js • Node.js • NoSQL • NPM • Nunjucks • PHP • Python • React • REST APIs • Sketch • Tailwind CSS • Twig • Vue • Webpack • WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer (Front End)

QuSecure

• Remote, USA

 Collaborated on the design and implementation of the user interface of the award winning QuProtect Software.

1 02/2024 - 07/2024

 Implemented React components using Tailwind CSS framework. Conducted code reviews, designed User Personae and ensured the user experience met the

highest standards of excellence.

Sr. Front End Developer (Project Consultant)

AIM Consulting Group

• Remote, USA **a** 04/2023 - 08/2023 Applied Material Design principles to create an intuitive user experience and a cohesive visual language across an Angular based User Management application.

· Leveraged AG Grid's advanced features, such as infinite scrolling, column pinning, and row grouping, to enhance data presentation.

Integrated backend REST APIs to fetch, display, and manipulate data.

Studio Senior Engineer

Deloitte Digital

New York, NY **1** 09/2021 - 01/2023 Established style guide and coding best practices in the development of an informational React.js website for the CDC.

 Conducted regular Standup meetings to ensure effective communication and collaboration within the team.

 Worked on building a custom Vue.js component for use with an AI chatbot and delivered an internal-facing Angular web application as part of a team.

Vice President, Institutional Securities Technology

Morgan Stanley

New York, NY

• Streamlined existing layouts and updated the framework and tools on the Angular front-end.

■ 03/2021 - 09/2021

· Worked on the UI of the internal-facing financial planning workbench application, focusing on improving the overall User Experience.

Senior UX Developer

Fashionphile

Lehi, UT

12/2018 - 03/2021

- Retooled CSS and JavaScript build processes to better integrate with new AWS CI/CD pipeline.
- Prototyped a new web application using Vue.js for Neiman Marcus stores to access the Fashionphile inventory system and led the development of the finished product.
- Refreshed the Customer Signup/Login flow to improve customer experience and security.
- · Guided the creation and implementation of a React component library using Next.js based on updated Style Guides.
- Mentored new Front-end Developers and helped establish coding standards and document best practices.

Web & UI Developer

Software Technology Group

· Completed projects for multiple clients including MRM/McCann, Cisco, Panasonic, Verizon, Fitbit, 7Tunnels, and Connect FSS.

Salt Lake City, UT **10/2017 - 12/2018**

· Worked on various web UI applications, product and promotional landing pages, as well as database-driven MVC applications.

Freelance Web & UI Developer

Freelance Contractor

Salt Lake City, UT **1**0/2016 - 10/2017 · Worked on multiple short-term projects for different companies, including website rebuild/redesign, new web application design, Shopify theme customizations, and implementing

Senior App Developer

Maverik Inc.

Salt Lake City, UT **3** 02/2016 - 09/2016 new features and fixes for both internal and public-facing web applications.

Front-End Web Developer

ZAGG Inc.

Salt Lake City, UT **■** 09/2012 - 10/2015 Created and maintained several Maverik company websites and applications, including a complete rebuild of an internal Maverik Real Estate Management app, updates to the Maverik Rewards Manager app, and changes to Triton (the internal store management site).

Front-End Web Developer

Overstock.com

responsive web design, and a migration to the Magento e-commerce platform.

Worked on a multitude of holiday, sale, and promotional web pages.

· Worked on numerous projects, including multiple product launches, moving the site to a

Salt Lake City, UT

Designed web banners and promo images.

■ 09/2010 - 02/2012 Maintained layout of the site's continuously evolving content.

EDUCATION

Neumont College of Computer Science

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science (unfinished) 2007 - 2009

PORTFOLIO & LINKS

Personal Website & Portfolio: https://donaldlivingston.com LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/donaldlivingston

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/dlivingston

Presentation at UtahJS Conference 2019: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iOZvkuTki2s